<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>System on CastOff</title>
    <link>https://christophe1997.github.io/tags/system/</link>
    <description>Recent content in System on CastOff</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh-cn</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy;Christophe</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 13:10:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://christophe1997.github.io/tags/system/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>进程</title>
      <link>https://christophe1997.github.io/posts/process/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 13:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christophe1997.github.io/posts/process/</guid>
      <description>The abstraction provided by the OS of a running program is something we call a process. And there are some APIs must be included in any interface of an operating system: create destroy wait miscellaneous control, most OS provide some kind of method to suspend a process and resume it. status, there are usually interfaces to get some status information about a process. The first thing that the OS must</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Address Space</title>
      <link>https://christophe1997.github.io/posts/address-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 23:54:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christophe1997.github.io/posts/address-space/</guid>
      <description>The Address Space The address space is the abstraction that OS is providing to the running program. The address space of a process contains all of the memory state of the running program. For example, the code of the program, the stack and the heap. In the sight of the program, it loaded into at a particular address and has a potentially very large address space, thus, we say that the OS is virtualizing memory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer System 4</title>
      <link>https://christophe1997.github.io/posts/computer-system-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 19:14:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christophe1997.github.io/posts/computer-system-4/</guid>
      <description>Linking Linking is the process of collecting and combining various pieces of code and data into a single file that can be loaded (copied) into memory and executed. Linking can be performed at compile time, when the source code is translated into machine code; at load time, when the program is loaded into memory and executed by the loader; and even at run time, by application programs. On modern systems, linking is performed automatically by programs called linkers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer System 3</title>
      <link>https://christophe1997.github.io/posts/computer-system-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 23:23:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christophe1997.github.io/posts/computer-system-3/</guid>
      <description>Optimization Writing an efficient program requires several type of activities. First, we must select an appropriate set of algorithms and data structures. Second, we must write source code that the compiler can effectively optimize to turn into efficient executable code. A third technique for dealing with especially demanding computations is to divide a task into portions that can be computed in parallel, on some combination of multiple cores and multiple processors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer System 2</title>
      <link>https://christophe1997.github.io/posts/computer-system-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 17:20:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christophe1997.github.io/posts/computer-system-2/</guid>
      <description>Assembler Computer execute machine code, sequences of bytes encoding the low-level operations that manipulate data manage memory, read and write data on storage devices, and communicate over networks.
We will focus on x86-64, the commonest machine language used in processor with laptop and PC, also it&amp;rsquo;s widely used in supercomputer and lager data center.
the x86-64 machine code is much different with the corresponding C code, the processor states below are everywhere:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer System 1</title>
      <link>https://christophe1997.github.io/posts/computer-system-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 23:54:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christophe1997.github.io/posts/computer-system-1/</guid>
      <description>Hardware Organization of A System A typical system has those hadrware below:
  Buses: Running throughout the system is a collection of electrical conduits called buses that carry bytes of ingormation back and forth betweent the components. Buses are typically designed to transfer fiexed sized chunks of bytes know as words. The number of bytes in a word is a fundamental system parameter that varies across systems. Most have word sizes of 8 bytes (64 bits)today</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
